[
{
"ans": "both a and c",
"language": "English",
"op1": "click on the new button.",
"op2": "both a and c",
"op3": "use the file new command",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "create a new blank presentation you could."
},
{
"ans": "edit",
"language": "English",
"op1": "insert",
"op2": "slideshow",
"op3": "format",
"op4": "edit",
"question": "in which menu change case command appears"
},
{
"ans": "in the custom animation task pane open effects of sun and shade the sound to play for the desired number of slides",
"language": "English",
"op1": "in the custom animation task pane open effects of sun and shade the sound to play for the desired number of slides",
"op2": "using the record sound feature press the record button and play your music as you click through the hall sensor",
"op3": "using the play CD audio track features set the CD to play for the desired number of task",
"op4": "all of the above",
"question": "how do you make an insert sound file play continuously over several slides"
},
{
"ans": "title box",
"language": "English",
"op1": "textbox",
"op2": "placeholder",
"op3": "bulletpoint",
"op4": "title box",
"question": "all area on flight that holds that takes to will appear in the presentation out line is a ______"
},
{
"ans": "all of the above",
"language": "English",
"op1": "create a professional and consistent look for your data",
"op2": "choose between standard table format that include border shading font colours and other formatting options",
"op3": "easily apply a consistent format through a workbook",
"op4": "all of the above",
"question": "the purpose of auto format command in excel is"
},
{
"ans": "all of the above",
"language": "English",
"op1": "a search engine does not discriminate between good and bad sites",
"op2": "I search engine display all web pages that contains your keyword and main list 1000 of an order result",
"op3": "a dictionary is a second attempt to categorise the best site available for a given subject for topic",
"op4": "all of the above",
"question": "which of the following statements about search engine and documentaries is true"
},
{
"ans": "all of the above",
"language": "English",
"op1": "130000",
"op2": "500000",
"op3": "1.1e+2",
"op4": "all of the above",
"question": "which one of the following can be entered as a number in a cell"
},
{
"ans": "spider",
"language": "English",
"op1": "spider",
"op2": "packets",
"op3": "cookies",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "which of the following search engine continuously sense of that start on a homepage of server and purpose all links stepwise"
},
{
"ans": "instant messaging",
"language": "English",
"op1": "instant messaging",
"op2": "email",
"op3": "usenet",
"op4": "blog",
"question": "what would you use for immediate real time communication with friend"
},
{
"ans": "packet switching",
"language": "English",
"op1": "circuit switching",
"op2": "packet switching",
"op3": "hybrid switching",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "the internet uses"
},
{
"ans": "bite bit field record file database",
"language": "English",
"op1": "bite bite record field file database",
"op2": "bite bit field record file database",
"op3": "bikebot record file field database",
"op4": "bit byte field record file database",
"question": "the ascending order of a data hierarchy"
},
{
"ans": "application",
"language": "English",
"op1": "system software",
"op2": "microcomputer",
"op3": "documentation",
"op4": "application",
"question": "software instruction intended to safety user a specific processing need are called"
},
{
"ans": "data in more useful or intelligible form",
"language": "English",
"op1": "RAW",
"op2": "data",
"op3": "data in more useful or intelligible form",
"op4": "alphanumeric data problem",
"question": "in computer terminology information means"
},
{
"ans": "arithmetic logic unit",
"language": "English",
"op1": "keyboard",
"op2": "printer",
"op3": "tape",
"op4": "arithmetic logic unit",
"question": "which of the following is a part of the central processing unit"
},
{
"ans": "knowing what a computer can and cannot do",
"language": "English",
"op1": "ability to write computer programs",
"op2": "knowing what a computer can and cannot do",
"op3": "knowing computer related vocabulary",
"op4": "ability to assemble computers",
"question": "what is mean by computer literacy"
},
{
"ans": "graphical presentation",
"language": "English",
"op1": "word processing",
"op2": "spreadsheet",
"op3": "database",
"op4": "graphical presentation",
"question": "the software application that is used to most often is"
},
{
"ans": "both circular task and sector",
"language": "English",
"op1": "circular task only",
"op2": "sectors only",
"op3": "both circular task and sector",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "floppy disk contains"
},
{
"ans": "homepage",
"language": "English",
"op1": "homepage",
"op2": "master page",
"op3": "first page",
"op4": "banner page",
"question": "the first page that you normally view at a view site is"
},
{
"ans": "to display a drop down list of justification options",
"language": "English",
"op1": "to display a drop down list of justification options",
"op2": "to display the four options for aligning text",
"op3": "to open the justification dialogue box",
"op4": "to centre the current line",
"question": "what is the function of justification button on the toolbar"
},
{
"ans": "2",
"language": "English",
"op1": "2",
"op2": "4",
"op3": "8",
"op4": "16",
"question": "the binary number system has a best"
},
{
"ans": "does calculations using addition subtraction multiplication and division",
"language": "English",
"op1": "check data for accuracy",
"op2": "does logical comparison such as equal to greater than less than both",
"op3": "does calculations using addition subtraction multiplication and division",
"op4": "c and b both",
"question": "the arithmetic logic unit performs following actions"
},
{
"ans": "first information is transferred to main memory and form their the CPU read",
"language": "English",
"op1": "directly",
"op2": "first information is transferred to main memory and form their the CPU read",
"op3": "through registers",
"op4": "none of this",
"question": "CPU read the information from secondary memory"
},
{
"ans": "an input device to produce good quality graphics",
"language": "English",
"op1": "an input device to produce good quality graphics",
"op2": "and output device to produce drawing and graphics",
"op3": "how fast output device using camera lenses",
"op4": "none of this",
"question": "a plotter is"
},
{
"ans": "menu bar",
"language": "English",
"op1": "buttons",
"op2": "menu bar",
"op3": "toolbar",
"op4": "None",
"question": "_______is a collection of buttons which represents various operations that can be carried out within an application"
},
{
"ans": "mathematical incentive scientific applications",
"language": "English",
"op1": "input output incentive processing",
"op2": "mathematical incentive scientific applications",
"op3": "data retrieval operations",
"op4": "none of these",
"question": "supercomputer are primarily used for"
},
{
"ans": "menu bar",
"language": "English",
"op1": "menu bar",
"op2": "tool bar",
"op3": "status bar",
"op4": "it display the name of the document or applications",
"question": "the top most bar in any application window is the ______"
},
{
"ans": "always use bleach to send message in different networks",
"language": "English",
"op1": "cannot address many users",
"op2": "does not provide protection given to first class mail",
"op3": "always use bleach to send message in different networks",
"op4": "none of this",
"question": "email"
},
{
"ans": "CorelDRAW",
"language": "English",
"op1": "CorelDRAW",
"op2": "MS Excel",
"op3": "MS word",
"op4": "none of this",
"question": "which of the following is graphical package"
},
{
"ans": "open the format menu",
"language": "English",
"op1": "open the format menu",
"op2": "to click the line spacing button",
"op3": "to select the paragraph you want to change",
"op4": "to open the paragraph menu",
"question": "what is the first step in MS word in changing line spacing"
},
{
"ans": "multimedia devices",
"language": "English",
"op1": "pointing devices",
"op2": "pen input device",
"op3": "data collection devices",
"op4": "multimedia devices",
"question": "a mouse drag bill and joystick are example of"
},
{
"ans": "file by some alternative names",
"language": "English",
"op1": "for saving the file for the first time to save",
"op2": "file by some alternative names",
"op3": "to save file in a format other than word",
"op4": "all of the above",
"question": "the save as dialogue box can be used"
},
{
"ans": "you copy other text",
"language": "English",
"op1": "you got other text",
"op2": "you shut down your computer",
"op3": "you copy other text",
"op4": "all of the above",
"question": "the contents of the clipboard remains the same until"
},
{
"ans": "all of the above",
"language": "English",
"op1": "you wish to add emphasize to particular paragraph",
"op2": "you wish to add and draw lines above and below or left or right of paragraph",
"op3": "you wish to surround the paragraph with different style of box",
"op4": "all of the above",
"question": "you probably use borders in world where"
},
{
"ans": "to both character as well as paragraph selection",
"language": "English",
"op1": "two paragraphs election only",
"op2": "two character selection only",
"op3": "to both character as well as paragraph selection",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "the formatting toolbar option are applied"
},
{
"ans": "create a new page at bottom of the document",
"language": "English",
"op1": "create a new page at the instruction.",
"op2": "create a new page at bottom of the document",
"op3": "create a new page that cannot be detected",
"op4": "create a blank page at the top of the document",
"question": "page break is used to do what"
},
{
"ans": "format",
"language": "English",
"op1": "format",
"op2": "tools",
"op3": "insert",
"op4": "table",
"question": "in which word menu letter Wizard command appears"
},
{
"ans": "table",
"language": "English",
"op1": "table",
"op2": "format",
"op3": "insert",
"op4": "tool",
"question": "in word split cells command appears in _______ menu"
},
{
"ans": "worksheet",
"language": "English",
"op1": "square",
"op2": "cubicle",
"op3": "sale",
"op4": "worksheet",
"question": "in excel the intersection of a row and column is called"
},
{
"ans": "in its default setting a word processor does not highlight the text",
"language": "English",
"op1": "in its default setting a word processor does not highlight the text",
"op2": "hibernating heaven you are dealing with the paint call amina text",
"op3": "by hibernating the look after justified days column will look greatly improved",
"op4": "Microsoft word highpoints text in its default setting",
"question": "one of the statements is not true"
},
{
"ans": "chart sheet",
"language": "English",
"op1": "chart sheet",
"op2": "embedded sheet",
"op3": "workbook",
"op4": "view chart",
"question": "a chart on same spreadsheet it's called"
},
{
"ans": "Netscape",
"language": "English",
"op1": "Netscape",
"op2": "Adobe edge",
"op3": "Firefox",
"op4": "Chrome",
"question": "first graphical browser for the www"
},
{
"ans": "a r p a n e t",
"language": "English",
"op1": "a r p a n e t",
"op2": "nsf net",
"op3": "v net",
"op4": "inet",
"question": "the network is planted seed of internet"
},
{
"ans": "all of the above",
"language": "English",
"op1": "presented by speaker",
"op2": "browser by individual",
"op3": "browser at kiosk",
"op4": "all of the above",
"question": "online is a PowerPoint slideshow options"
},
{
"ans": "a and b both",
"language": "English",
"op1": "fill weekdays",
"op2": "fill series",
"op3": "a and b both",
"op4": "none of this",
"question": "in Excel shortcut film menu contains"
},
{
"ans": "both a and b",
"language": "English",
"op1": "set print area from file menu",
"op2": "set print area from file page setup",
"op3": "both a and b",
"op4": "none of this",
"question": "to print specific area in Excel"
},
{
"ans": "सही",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "सही",
"op2": "गलत",
"op3": "बता नही सकते",
"op4": "इन्मे से कोई भी नही",
"question": "माऊस 1 इनपुट उपकरण है"
},
{
"ans": "abs",
"language": "English",
"op1": "char",
"op2": "len",
"op3": "var",
"op4": "abs",
"question": "which of the following is not text function"
},
{
"ans": "abs",
"language": "English",
"op1": "char",
"op2": "len",
"op3": "var",
"op4": "abs",
"question": "which of the following is not text function"
},
{
"ans": "abacus",
"language": "English",
"op1": "abacus",
"op2": "calculator",
"op3": "anatur",
"op4": "none of above",
"question": "first computer is"
},
{
"ans": "advanced micro devices",
"language": "English",
"op1": "advantage micro distance",
"op2": "and mad dam",
"op3": "advanced micro devices",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "AMD stands for"
},
{
"ans": "compact disk recordable",
"language": "English",
"op1": "compact disk recordable",
"op2": "collect data radium",
"op3": "colour data ring",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "CD_R stands for"
},
{
"ans": "optical mark reader",
"language": "English",
"op1": "optical mark reader",
"op2": "optical mark reading",
"op3": "optical mark radar",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "OMR stands for"
},
{
"ans": "local area network",
"language": "English",
"op1": "local area network",
"op2": "limited area network",
"op3": "limit and notice",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "lAN stands for"
},
{
"ans": "world wide web",
"language": "English",
"op1": "world wide web",
"op2": "world wide websites",
"op3": "world wider web",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "www stands for"
},
{
"ans": "terra byte",
"language": "English",
"op1": "tina byte",
"op2": "terra byte",
"op3": "team byte",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "TB stands for"
},
{
"ans": "basic input output system",
"language": "English",
"op1": "basic input output system",
"op2": "BIO settlement",
"op3": "BIOSSS",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "what is the full form of BIOS"
},
{
"ans": "ctrl+c",
"language": "English",
"op1": "ctrl+B",
"op2": "ctrl+c",
"op3": "ctrl+A",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "what is the shortcut key of copy"
},
{
"ans": "ctrl+X",
"language": "English",
"op1": "ctrl+X",
"op2": "ctrl+C",
"op3": "ctrl+M",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "what is the shortcut key for CUT"
},
{
"ans": "ctrl+V",
"language": "English",
"op1": "ctrl+V",
"op2": "ctrl+A",
"op3": "ctrl+B",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "what is the shortcut key for PASTE"
},
{
"ans": "ctrl+B",
"language": "English",
"op1": "ctrl+C",
"op2": "ctrl+B",
"op3": "ctrl+A",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "what is the shortcut key for BOLD"
},
{
"ans": "F1",
"language": "English",
"op1": "F1",
"op2": "F2",
"op3": "F4",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "what is the shortcut key for help"
},
{
"ans": "none of the above",
"language": "English",
"op1": "F2",
"op2": "F3",
"op3": "F4",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "what is the shortcut key for search"
},
{
"ans": "ctrl+Alt+Del",
"language": "English",
"op1": "ctrl+Alt+Del",
"op2": "Alt+Del",
"op3": "Del",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "what is the shortcut key for REBOOT"
},
{
"ans": "ctrl+K",
"language": "English",
"op1": "ctrl+K",
"op2": "G",
"op3": "K",
"op4": "none of the above",
"question": "what is the shortcut key for HYPERLINK"
},
{
"ans": "android",
"language": "English",
"op1": "C",
"op2": "C++",
"op3": "Java",
"op4": "android",
"question": "this is not programming language"
},
{
"ans": "2",
"language": "English",
"op1": "1",
"op2": "2",
"op3": "3",
"op4": "4",
"question": "how many scroll bars can be visible on the text area if your document is over 200% …../"
},
{
"ans": "insert",
"language": "English",
"op1": "view",
"op2": "refrence",
"op3": "insert",
"op4": "page layout",
"question": "what ribbon will you find where you can add a chart? "
},
{
"ans": "page Layout",
"language": "English",
"op1": "view",
"op2": "refrence",
"op3": "insert",
"op4": "page layout",
"question": "What ribbon do you use to change margins? "
},
{
"ans": "Number of pages in the document, word count,",
"language": "English",
"op1": "Number of pages in the document, word count,",
"op2": "size of margins, word count, web layout",
"op3": "Number of spellings errors, page number, document name",
"op4": "name of document, insert button, spell check",
"question": "What Can be Shown on the status bar?……"
},
{
"ans": "Both (1) and (2)",
"language": "English",
"op1": "Is placed just below the standard toolbar",
"op2": "Is used to apply common formats to the worksheet test selection, like making it bold, italics, underlined or changing the font style and size",
"op3": "Both (1) and (2) ",
"op4": "None of the above",
"question": "The formatting toolbar/"
},
{
"ans": "B$2:B$9",
"language": "English",
"op1": "B2:B9",
"op2": "$B$2:%B$9",
"op3": "B$2:B$9",
"op4": "None of the above",
"question": "To change the cell reference B2: B9 to an absolute row and column reference, you word enter it is as ….. "
},
{
"ans": "All below",
"language": "English",
"op1": "All below",
"op2": "Can be built using function wizard ",
"op3": "Is a shortcut formula ",
"op4": "Is a readymade formula ",
"question": "A function in Excel ….. "
},
{
"ans": "SUM",
"language": "English",
"op1": "FV",
"op2": "SUM",
"op3": "NPV",
"op4": "PMT",
"question": "Which of the following is not a financial function?"
},
{
"ans": "ABS()",
"language": "English",
"op1": "CHAR()",
"op2": "LEN()",
"op3": "VAR()",
"op4": "ABS()",
"question": "Which of the following is not a text function?"
},
{
"ans": "edu domain",
"language": "English",
"op1": "mail domain",
"op2": "in domain",
"op3": "edu domain",
"op4": "com domain",
"question": "Computers on the internet owned and operated by education institution form part of the …"
},
{
"ans": "First Web page ",
"language": "English",
"op1": "User Web page ",
"op2": "First Web page ",
"op3": "Begining  Web page ",
"op4": "Home Page",
"question": "All web addresses start ….."
},
{
"ans": "Home Page",
"language": "English",
"op1": "User Web page ",
"op2": "First Web page ",
"op3": "Begining  Web page ",
"op4": "Home Page",
"question": "When you start a web browser the first web page that gets loaded in the browser is called …"
},
{
"ans": "both (1) and (2)",
"language": "English",
"op1": "E-mail, Telnet, Usenet ",
"op2": "Sound and movie files ",
"op3": "both (1) and (2) ",
"op4": "All internet communication tools ",
"question": "The world wide web integrates which of the following?"
},
{
"ans": "TRUE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "Using home tab you can perform editing functions such as cut, copy, paste, find  and replace etc. …"
},
{
"ans": "TRUE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "Using insert menu you can insert various object such as page numbers, headers and footers, picture etc…"
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "using review tab you can aces to various utilities of word such as spess check, macros and mail merge etc. …"
},
{
"ans": "TRUE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "In MS word every command is available is ribbon. ……. MS"
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "Formula bar is available in MS Word 2010…."
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "To create a new worksheet, select worksheet from the file menu……"
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "Cells are named by their positions either by rows or coloumns…."
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "if the bold and underline buttons are appearing lighter than before, it means that they are currently in use …"
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "Standard width of a column is 18.43……"
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "To open a file quickly from the open dialog box, double click the file’s icon. "
},
{
"ans": "TRUE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "To specify multiple recipients of carbon copy of same mail message, Cc: field is used…"
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "In SMTP, the message can be of any length…… SMTP"
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "A protocol used for fetching e-mail from a mailbox is PQPI…"
},
{
"ans": "FALSE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "All incoming email messages are to be stored in the outbox folder"
},
{
"ans": "TRUE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "he email component of internet explorer is called  “outlook Express”"
},
{
"ans": "TRUE",
"language": "English",
"op1": "TRUE",
"op2": "FALSE",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "The input device to be used to get a printed diagram into a computer is the …"
},
{
"ans": "input device",
"language": "English",
"op1": "output device",
"op2": "input device",
"op3": "game pad",
"op4": "scanner",
"question": "What type of device is a computer mouse?"
},
{
"ans": "Hardware",
"language": "English",
"op1": "Software",
"op2": "Peripheral",
"op3": "Hardware",
"op4": "Storage",
"question": "any component of the computer you can see and touch is called"
},
{
"ans": "Tools",
"language": "English",
"op1": "All below",
"op2": "Edit",
"op3": "Window",
"op4": "Tools",
"question": " In which menu spelling command appears"
},
{
"ans": "show a context-sensitive menu ",
"language": "English",
"op1": "open the Display Properties dialog box ",
"op2": "show a context-sensitive menu ",
"op3": "open the Control Panel ",
"op4": "minimize all open applications",
"question": "A right click on the Windows desktop itself will _____. "
},
{
"ans": "Right-aligned",
"language": "English",
"op1": "Justified",
"op2": "Right-aligned",
"op3": "Center-aligned ",
"op4": "Left-aligned ",
"question": "When numbers are typed inside a cell, the default alignment is:"
},
{
"ans": "absolute cell reference ",
"language": "English",
"op1": "relative cell reference ",
"op2": "absolute cell reference ",
"op3": "mixed cell reference ",
"op4": "All of the above",
"question": "Cell address A$4 in a formula means it is a"
},{
"ans": "अबॅकस",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "कॅल्क्युलेटर",
"op2": "अबॅकस",
"op3": "फोन",
"op4": "वैदिक गणित",
"question": "पहलाकम्प्युटर ये है."
},
{
"ans": "सीसीएस",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "एसएमटीपी",
"op2": "पीओपी",
"op3": "एफ टी पी",
"op4": "सीसीएस",
"question": "इसमें कोनसा प्रोटोकॉल गलत है "
},
{
"ans": "बीट",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "बाईट",
"op2": "बीट",
"op3": "केबी",
"op4": "जीबी",
"question": "इसमें कोनसाछोटा है "
},
{
"ans": "युनिक्स",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "युनिक्स",
"op2": "बेसिक",
"op3": "लिप्स",
"op4": "java",
"question": "इसमें कोनसी प्रोग्रामिंग नहीं है "
},
{
"ans": "इनबॉक्स",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "इनबॉक्स",
"op2": "आउट बॉक्स",
"op3": "ड्राफ्ट",
"op4": "सेंड बॉक्स",
"question": "आया मेल यहाँपे सेवहोता है "
},
{
"ans": "सही",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "सही",
"op2": "गलत",
"op3": "बता नहीं सकते ",
"op4": "इनमेसे कोही नहीं",
"question": "माउस ये इनपुट उपकरण है "
},
{
"ans": "गलत",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "सही",
"op2": "गलत",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "ईमेल आयडी केस सेन्सिटिव्ह होता है"
},
{
"ans": "गलत",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "सही",
"op2": "गलत",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "ctrl +o शॉर्टकट की का प्रयोग नया प्यारा बनाने के लिए होता है"
},
{
"ans": "हमेशा",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "30 दिन",
"op2": "100 दिन",
"op3": "हमेशा",
"op4": "500 दिन",
"question": "एक फोल्डर में एक मेसेज कितने टाइम तक रहता है"
},
{
"ans": "इनपुट",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "इनपुट",
"op2": "आउटपुट",
"op3": "स्टोरेज",
"op4": "none",
"question": "कीबोर्ड किस प्रकार की डिवाइस है"
},
{
"ans": "सही",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "सही",
"op2": "गलत",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "x25 पॅकेत स्विचींग नेटवर्क एक उदाहरण है"
},
{
"ans": "गलत",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "सही",
"op2": "गलत",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "ई-मेल मे सिर्फ टेक्स्ट लिंक कर भेज सकते है"
},
{
"ans": "गलत",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "सही",
"op2": "गलत",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "कंट्रोल प्लस एल शोर्टकट के अंडरलाईन के लिये प्रयोग होता है"
},
{
"ans": "false",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "true",
"op2": "false",
"op3": "both a b",
"op4": "depends on data",
"question": "foreign key can be null"
},
{
"ans": "बायनारी digit",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "मेगाबाईट",
"op2": "बायनारी digit",
"op3": "बाईट",
"op4": "बायनरी नंबर",
"question": "इनमे से सबसे छोटा क्या है"
},
{
"ans": "दो लाख",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "पचास हजार",
"op2": "दो लाख",
"op3": "100000",
"op4": "कोई नही",
"question": "PMJJBY मे कितने अमाऊंट तक इन्शुरन्स है"
},
{
"ans": "जमाओ पर",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "जमाओ पर",
"op2": "त्रुण पर",
"op3": "a and b",
"op4": "none",
"question": "बैंक ब्याज देता है"
},
{
"ans": "लाईट पेन",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "फ्लोटर",
"op2": "मॉनिटर",
"op3": "लाईट पेन",
"op4": "प्रिंटर",
"question": "इनमे से कोण आउटपुट डिवाइस नही है"
},
{
"ans": "",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "सही",
"op2": "गलत",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "ई-मेल से कोई भी इन्फॉर्मेशन सेंड करनी है तो सिर्फ एक या दो लोगो को ही भेज सकते है"
},
{
"ans": "सही",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "सही",
"op2": "गलत",
"op3": "-",
"op4": "-",
"question": "वेब कॅम कम्प्युटर मे व्हिडिओ के लिए प्रयोग किया जाता है"
},
{
"ans": "100 metre",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "200 metre",
"op2": "100 metre",
"op3": "500 metre",
"op4": "700 metre",
"question": "एसटीपी केबल का अधिकतम लेन्थ है"
},
{
"ans": "graphical user interface",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "greater user interface",
"op2": "graphics user interface",
"op3": "graphical user interface",
"op4": "graphical user internet",
"question": "GUI पूर्ण स्वरूप क्या है"
},
{
"ans": "दुर्घटना बिमा पोलिसी",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "लाइफ इन्शुरन्स पॉलिसी",
"op2": "दुर्घटना बिमा पोलिसी",
"op3": "स्वास्थ्य बीमा पॉलिसी",
"op4": "इन्मे से कोई नही",
"question": "PMJJBY क्या है"
},
{
"ans": "ctrl + a",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "ctrl + a",
"op2": "ctrl + l",
"op3": "ctrl + j",
"op4": "ctrl + r",
"question": "इनमे से कोनसी अलाइनमेंट की शॉर्टकट की नही है"
},
{
"ans": "मॉनिटर",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "मॉनिटर",
"op2": "पेन ड्राईव्ह",
"op3": "रॅम",
"op4": "मोडेम",
"question": "इन्मे से कौन सी डिवाइस डाटा स्टोरेज नही है"
},
{
"ans": "a and b",
"language": "Hindi",
"op1": "new बटन पे क्लिक करे",
"op2": "new कमांड पर क्लिक करे",
"op3": "a and b",
"op4": "इनमे कोई नही",
"question": "नया प्रेजेंटेशन बनाने के लिए "
},
{
"ans": "अबॅकस",
"language": "Marathi",
"op1": "कॅल्क्युलेटर",
"op2": "अबॅकस",
"op3": "फोन",
"op4": "वैदिक गणित",
"question": "पहिला कम्प्युटर याला म्हणतात ."
},
{
"ans": "सीसीएस",
"language": "Marathi",
"op1": "एसएमटीपी",
"op2": "पीओपी",
"op3": "एफ टी पी",
"op4": "सीसीएस",
"question": "यामध्ये कोणता प्रोटॉकल चुकीचा आहे"
},
{
"ans": "बीट",
"language": "Marathi",
"op1": "बाईट",
"op2": "बीट",
"op3": "केबी",
"op4": "जीबी",
"question": "डेटाचा सर्वात छोटे मोजमाप काय आहे"
},
{
"ans": "युनिक्स",
"language": "English",
"op1": "युनिक्स",
"op2": "बेसिक",
"op3": "लिप्स",
"op4": "java",
"question": "या मधली कोणती लँग्वेज प्रोग्रामिंग लँग्वेज नाही"
},
{
"ans": "इनबॉक्स",
"language": "Marathi",
"op1": "इनबॉक्स",
"op2": "आउट बॉक्स",
"op3": "ड्राफ्ट",
"op4": "सेंड बॉक्स",
"question": "आलेला मेलिया मध्ये सेव्ह होतो"
},
{
"ans": "बरोबर",
"language": "Marathi",
"op1": "बरोबर",
"op2": "चूक",
"op3": "सांगता येत नाही",
"op4": "वरीलपैकी कोणीच नाही",
"question": "इनपुट माऊस हे एक इनपुट उपकरण आहे"
},
      {
        "ans" : "वरील सर्व",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "एटीएम कार्ड",
        "op2" : "क्रेडिट कार्ड",
        "op3" : "इंटरनेट बँकिंग ",
        "op4" : "वरील सर्व",
        "question" : "ऑनलाईन खरेदीसाठी कोणाचा उपयोग होतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "Microsoft",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "IBM",
        "op2" : "Oracle",
        "op3" : "Google",
        "op4" : "Microsoft",
        "question" : "edge browser कोणत्या कंपनीने बनवलं"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "बरोबर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "चूक",
        "op2" : "बरोबर",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "www चा पूर्ण रूप वर्ल्ड वाईड वेब आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "बरोबर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चूक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "auto correction ने स्पेलिंग आपले आप करेक्ट होत जातात"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "बरोबर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चूक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "माऊस ची सेटिंग बदलली जाऊ शकते"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "१०२४ byte",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "१०२४ byte",
        "op2" : "१०२४bit",
        "op3" : "१०२४MB",
        "op4" : "१०००bit",
        "question" : "kilobytes =?"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "चूक",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "चूक",
        "op2" : "बरोबर",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "प्रोजेक्शन मध्ये पिक्चर इन्सर्ट करण्यासाठी प्लेस होल्डर आवश्यक आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "चूक",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "चूक",
        "op2" : "बरोबर",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "कोणत्याही कॉम्प्युटरचा आयपी ऍड्रेस जाऊ शकत नाही"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "f5",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "f5",
        "op2" : "f4",
        "op3" : "f7",
        "op4" : "f10",
        "question" : "एम एस एक्सेल मध्ये गोटू मेन्यूवर जाण्यासाठी शॉर्टकट की काय आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "BUS",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "BUS",
        "op2" : "RING",
        "op3" : "network",
        "op4" : "MESH",
        "question" : "कम्प्युटरच्या सर्व उपकरणांना समांतर लाईनमध्ये जोडण्या ला काय म्हणतात"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "जमा  वर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "जमा  वर",
        "op2" : "कर्जा वर",
        "op3" : "a and b",
        "op4" : "none",
        "question" : "बैंक व्याज देते"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "यापैकी नाही",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "खाते फॉर्म",
        "op2" : "नोमिनी फॉर्म",
        "op3" : "ओळखपत्र",
        "op4" : "यापैकी नाही",
        "question" : "उत्तराधिकारी बनविण्यासाठी त्यांची सही ही कोठे उपयोग आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "चूक",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चूक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "एकावेळेस आपण केवळ फक्त एकच ई-मेल डिलीट करू"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "पेज ओरिएंटेशन",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "पेज ओरिएंटेशन",
        "op2" : "पेज सा इज",
        "op3" : "पेज लेआउट",
        "op4" : "पेज वि यू",
        "question" : "____हे लांडस्कॅपे आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "12",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "16",
        "op2" : "12",
        "op3" : "19",
        "op4" : "14",
        "question" : "कीबोर्ड मध्ये फंक्शन की किती आहेत"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "चूक",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चूक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "ram....1123@gmail.com बरोबर मेल आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "सुपर कम्प्युटर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "मिनी कम्प्युटर",
        "op2" : "मायक्रॉकम्प्युटर",
        "op3" : "सुपर कम्प्युटर",
        "op4" : "मेनफ्रेम कंप्यूटर",
        "question" : " सगळ्यात मोठा कॉम्प्युटर कोणता आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "public provident fund",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "permanent public fund",
        "op2" : "public permanent fund",
        "op3" : "public private fund",
        "op4" : "public provident fund",
        "question" : "PPF चा फुल फॉर्म आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "चूक",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चूक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "http व html दोन स्टैंडर्ड प्रोटोकॉल आहेत"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "MAN",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "lAN",
        "op2" : "MAN",
        "op3" : "WAN",
        "op4" : "वरील सर्व",
        "question" : "कोणतीही संस्था किंवा कंपनीसाठी कोणतं नेटवर्क वापरलं जातो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "mosaic",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "Mozilla",
        "op2" : "Internet explorer",
        "op3" : "mosaic",
        "op4" : "Opera",
        "question" : "खालीलपैकी कोणता पहिला वेब ब्राउझर होता"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "वरील सर्व",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "driver load करणे",
        "op2" : "सर्व हार्डवेअर ला चेक करणे",
        "op3" : "ऑपरेटिंग सिस्टिम लोड करणे",
        "op4" : "वरील सर्व",
        "question" : "BIOS च कार्य काय आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "चूक",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चूक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : " .",
        "question" : "बुकमार्क मध्ये कार्य करत असताना कूल 6 नेव्हिगेटर प्राप्त होते"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "काही सीमा नाही",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "पन्नास करोड",
        "op2" : "शंभर करोड",
        "op3" : "एक हजार करोड पेक्षा जास्त",
        "op4" : "काही सीमा नाही",
        "question" : "चेकच्या साहाय्याने आपण किती पैसे काढू शकतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "न्यूज ग्रुप",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "ई-मेल सर्विस",
        "op2" : "न्यूज ग्रुप",
        "op3" : "इंटरनेट सर्व्हिस",
        "op4" : "वरील सर्व",
        "question" : "युज नेट काय आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "Archie, created in 1990by Alan Emtage",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "WebCrawler",
        "op2" : "AltaVista",
        "op3" : "Dogpile",
        "op4" : "Archie, created in 1990by Alan Emtage",
        "question" : "सर्वात पहिलं सर्च इंजिन कोणतं होतं"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "thin film tranjister",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "थीन फिल्म ट्यूब",
        "op2" : "thin film tranjister",
        "op3" : "thin फिल्म ट्रॅक",
        "op4" : "thin फिल्म ट्रान्सफर",
        "question" : "टीएफटी चा पूर्ण रूप काय आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "internet",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "नेटवर्क",
        "op2" : "LAN",
        "op3" : "MAN",
        "op4" : "internet",
        "question" : "पर्सनल कम्प्युटर मध्ये ई-मेल आणि रिसीव्ह हेतू कशाच्या साह्याने ईनेबल झाला पाहिजे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "७",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "४",
        "op2" : "५",
        "op3" : "७",
        "op4" : "८",
        "question" : "OSI मॉडेल मध्ये किती लेयर असतात"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "रिसायकल बिन",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "रिसायकल बिन",
        "op2" : "डेस्कटॉप",
        "op3" : "ए आणि बी",
        "op4" : "कोणीच नाही",
        "question" : "डिलिट केलेली फाईल कुठे पाहता येते"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "बरोबर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "चूक",
        "op2" : "बरोबर",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "ई-मेल ऍड्रेस मध्ये युजर नेम व डोमेन नेम @ सिम्बॉल वेगळे केले जातात"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "रजिस्टर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "राम स्पेस",
        "op2" : "रजिस्टर",
        "op3" : "बाईट स्पेस",
        "op4" : "वरील सर्व",
        "question" : "सीपीयू चा ए एल यु मध्ये असते"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "2015",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "2014",
        "op2" : "2015",
        "op3" : "2016",
        "op4" : "2017",
        "question" : "प्रधानमंत्री  जीवन ज्योती विमा योजना सुरुवात कधी झाली "
      },
      {
        "ans" : "माय सर्च",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "गुगल",
        "op2" : "याहू",
        "op3" : "बाय डू",
        "op4" : "माय सर्च",
        "question" : "यापैकी कोणता सर्च इंजिन नाही"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "कंट्रोल+शिफ्ट+$",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "कंट्रोल+शिफ्ट+सी",
        "op2" : "कंट्रोल+शिफ्ट+$",
        "op3" : "शिफ्ट+सी",
        "op4" : "ए एल टी+कंट्रोल+सी",
        "question" : "एम एस एक्सेल मध्ये करन्सी फॉरमॅट apply करण्यासाठी कोणती शॉर्टकट की आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "क्लिप बोर्ड",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "रिसायकल बिन",
        "op2" : "क्लिप बोर्ड",
        "op3" : "माय कम्प्युटर",
        "op4" : "डेस्कटॉप",
        "question" : "कट व कॉपी करण्यासाठी सिलेक्टेड टॅक्स कुठे सेव होते"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "ए आणि बी दोन्ही",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "भारतीय नागरिक",
        "op2" : "NRI",
        "op3" : "ए आणि बी दोन्ही",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "खातक कोण उघडू शकतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "Timothy John berners-lee",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "Charles Babbage",
        "op2" : "Timothy John berners-lee",
        "op3" : "Marc andreessen ",
        "op4" : "Eric Bina",
        "question" : "www चे जनक कोण आहेत"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "प्रोसेसर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "प्रोसेसर",
        "op2" : "इनपुट डिवाइस",
        "op3" : "प्रोग्रॅम",
        "op4" : "प्रोटेक्टर",
        "question" : "एक हार्डवेअर डिवाइस जे डाटा ला इंफॉर्मेशन मध्ये रूपांतर करतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "8एप्रिल 2015",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "8 ऑगस्ट 2015",
        "op2" : "8एप्रिल 2015",
        "op3" : "8 एप्रिल 2014",
        "op4" : "८ मे 2015",
        "question" : "प्रधानमंत्री मुद्रा योजनाची सुरुवात कधी झाली"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "वरील सर्व",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "RD",
        "op2" : "FD",
        "op3" : "Saving account",
        "op4" : "वरील सर्व",
        "question" : "खालीलपैकी कशात नॉमिनी जोडला जाऊ शकतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "बरोबर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चूक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "स्माईली लेखकाच्या चेहऱ्यावरची अभिव्यक्ती प्रदर्शित करतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "cut",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "cut",
        "op2" : "paste",
        "op3" : "cut , copy",
        "op4" : "undo",
        "question" : "ctrl+x शॉर्टकट की आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "गणना",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "मापन",
        "op2" : "गणना",
        "op3" : "विद्युत",
        "op4" : "लॉजिकल",
        "question" : "डिजिटल कम्प्युटर कोणत्या या सिद्धांतावर काम करते"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "256",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "254",
        "op2" : "255",
        "op3" : "256",
        "op4" : "257",
        "question" : "वर्कशीट च्या एका सेलमध्ये जास्तीत जास्त किती कॅरेक्टर ठेवू शकतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "कंट्रोल+शिफ्ट+#",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "कंट्रोल+;",
        "op2" : "शिफ्ट+;",
        "op3" : "कंट्रोल+शिफ्ट+#",
        "op4" : "कंट्रोल+शिफ्ट+$",
        "question" : "एम एस एक्सेल सेलमध्ये ______े डेट फॉर्मेट करण्याची शॉर्टकट की आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "बरोबर",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चुक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "डिफॉल्ट वर्कशीट मध्ये बॅकग्राऊंड बदल जाऊ शकतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "1जीबी",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "शंभर एम बी",
        "op2" : "1जीबी",
        "op3" : "दहा जीबी",
        "op4" : " 1 TB",
        "question" : "एक अरब ब्युटस_____\"बरोबर आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "चूक",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चूक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "एक्सेल वर्कशीट मध्ये सिलेक्ट ऑल चा ऑप्शन टूलबार मध्ये राईट साईड ला असतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "ग्राफिकल युजर इंटरफेस",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "ग्रुप यूजर इंटर्फेस",
        "op2" : "ग्राफिकल युजर इंटरफेस",
        "op3" : "ग्राफ यूजर इंटरफेस",
        "op4" : "वरीलपैकी कोणीही नाही",
        "question" : "GUI चा चा फुल फॉर्म काय आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "चुक",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "बरोबर",
        "op2" : "चुक",
        "op3" : ".",
        "op4" : ".",
        "question" : "ctrl+tab  ने एक्सेल मध्ये एक्सेल मधून दुसऱ्या सेलमध्ये मुव्ह करू शकतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "नेटवर्क",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "कम्युनिकेशन",
        "op2" : "आउटपुट",
        "op3" : "नेटवर्क",
        "op4" : "इनपुट",
        "question" : "राउटर कोणत्या प्रकारचा डिवाइस आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "वरील सर्व",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "संपत्तीचे पेपर जमा करून बँक मधून घेतलेले पैसे",
        "op2" : "सोने बँक मध्ये जमा करून घेतलेले पैसे",
        "op3" : "शिक्षणासाठी बँकेकडून घेतलेले पैसे",
        "op4" : "वरील सर्व",
        "question" : "ऋण कशास म्हणतात"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "यु एल एस आय सी",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "एस एसआय सी",
        "op2" : "एम एस आय सी",
        "op3" : "व्ही एल एसआय सी",
        "op4" : "यु एल एस आय सी",
        "question" : "आजच्या पिढीच्या कम्प्युटर मध्ये याचा उपयोग योग होतो"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "tax deducted at source",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "tax deducted for a source",
        "op2" : "tax deducted at source",
        "op3" : "tax deducted from source",
        "op4" : "tax deducted from all source",
        "question" : "टीडीएस चे पूर्ण रूप काय आहे"
      },
      {
        "ans" : "indian government",
        "language" : "Marathi",
        "op1" : "RBI",
        "op2" : "SBI",
        "op3" : "indian government",
        "op4" : "वरील सर्व",
        "question" : "कॉइन कोण जाहीर करतो"
      }
    
 
]
